A Guide to the Papers of Dorothy Lippincott 1974-1978
Special Collections, Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Special Collections, Perry Library, Old Dominion University
The Papers of Dorothy Lippincott 1974-1978
Special Collections, Perry Library, Old Dominion University
RG 6 - 4B
One Hollinger Document case.
Administrative Information
Access
The collection is open to researchers without restrictions.
Biographical/Historical Information
Dorothy Lippincott received her bachelors degree from the College of William and Mary and her Master of Science in Education from Old Dominion University. She began working at the Norfolk Division of the College of William and Mary in 1957. One year later, Mrs. Lippincott was appointed full time director of College Relations and Placement. In that capacity, she established Old Dominion's first Placement Office and organized its first formal recruitment programs by businesses, government, and industry. She was also responsible for developing annual Federal Career Days, business and industrial career conferences, campus wide alumni celebrations, the first general information folder at Old Dominion University, departmental brochures, a campus wide calendar of events. Mrs. Lippincott was also the coordinator of Old Dominion University's first appearance and victory on the G.E. College Bowl television program in 1970.
Eventually, Mrs. Lippincott was named to serve as liaison between Old Dominion University and the news media, In that capacity, she coordinated a half-hour program on WTAR radio. In addition, she handled various special events at the University such as the dedication of new buildings or facilities. At the same time she developed the Old Dominion Univerity Speakers Bureau and worked very closely with organizations such as Town-N-Gown and the Faculty Wives Club. After a long and distinguished career, Mrs. Lippincott retired on July 1, 1974.
Scope and Content Information
The collection includes: correspondence; the records of Town-N-Gown; a report on Norfolk Division of William and Mary; activities at Old Dominion University; and assorted brochures. Mrs. Lippincott participated in the growth of the university as one of its most able administrators. Among her papers the records of Town-N-Gown represent an interesting new phase of university history just as a report entitled "The College of William and Mary in Norfolk" represents an earlier one.
Contents List
- Correspondence (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 1)
- Memoranda: Monthly Meetings of the Town-N-Gown Board, May 1974-March 1975 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 2)
- Minutes of the Town-N-Gown Board, May 1974-April 1976 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 3)
- President's Report, Town-N-Gown, 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 4)
- Memoranda: Monthly Meetings of the Town-N-Gown Board, September 1975-May 1976 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 5)
- President's Report, Town-N-Gown, 1975-1976 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 6)
- Nominations for Officers of the Town-N-Gown Board, 1975-1976 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 7)
- Town-N-Gown Executive Board, 1975-1976 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 8)
- Town-N-Gown Executive Board, 1976-1977 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 9)
- Town-N-Gown Chairmen and Presidents, 1965-1977 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 10)
- Town-N-Gown Activities, 1965-1977 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 11)
- Town-N-Gown Brochures, 1976-1977 and 1977-1978 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 12)
- Pamphlet: The College of William and Mary in Norfolk (Report) (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 13)
- Activities at Old Dominion University (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 14)
- Assorted Brochures (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 15)